Salahuddin

Program Analyst, Digital Financial Services (DFS)

Islamabad, Pakistan | 92 315 819 7578 | salahu@bu.edu | linkedin.com/in/sallauddinn

SUMMARY

Passionate, self-motivated and diligent professional with 4+ years of experience in project management, program monitoring and evaluation, and proposal development. Highly adept at planning, researching and reporting program activities as well as performing data analysis, preparing policy briefs, and literature reviews.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Program Analyst, DFS

Mar 2020 - Present

Karandaaz Pakistan | Islamabad, Pakistan

Assisting a portfolio of projects in support of strategic goals of the program including providing budget oversight and planning, financial analysis, financial reporting, and/or portfolio operations support. Working closely with the Program Manager and the DFS team, as well as the stakeholders including Donor (BMGF), DFS Advisory Committee and the Board. Salient accomplishments and responsibilities include:

- Developed the proposal and the results framework for the integration of BISP with Raast (Pakistan's first Instant Payment System).
- Successfully developed workflow processes and procedures to integrate data driven approaches at various stages of grant development.
- Conducted industry analysis and research to inform the future DFS strategies and successfully drove the strategic planning process for the DFS unit.
- Built custom dashboards and gantt charts in Tableau to track program performance, financial performance, and impact numbers and reconstructed the data repository to improve access to information.
- Successfully led the implementation of ERP within the DFS unit.
- Managing the planning and monitoring of the overall program activities including progress reporting, due diligence, compliance, and budgeting.
- Responsible for aligning the project deliverables and outputs to the program's outcomes and progress indicators. Prepare briefing material, presentations, and program performance reports for donors and management on a frequent basis.
- Assisting in grant development and approvals by providing technical advice on requisite narratives, proposals
 and memos.

Management Trainee

Aug 2016 - Jan 2018

The Aman Foundation | Karachi, Pakistan

As part of the The Aman Foundation's flagship Management Trainee Programme, worked on practical and challenging assignments and developed relevant knowledge, abilities, and managerial skills. Worked as the Secretary to the Operating Committee at the Aman Foundation and assisted the management in developing frameworks and models for social impact measurement. Salient job responsibilities and accomplishments included:

- Effectively monitored the implementation of the project Subah-e-Kiran, aimed at improving the socio-economic lives of marginalized women in Karachi. Signed MOUs with multiple textile industry leaders in Karachi for the placement of female beneficiaries.
- Successfully prepared a feasibility study for experimental and innovative technical trainings at the AmanTech.
- Designed and conducted a survey to identify the key reasons for under-investment in the upskilling and reskilling of technical staff at various factories in Karachi.
- Participated in the preparation of new projects, including development of project concept notes and project appraisal documents.
- Coordinated awareness sessions and training courses for the capacity building of technical staff at multiple companies in Karachi.

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Coordinator Feb 2016 - Jul 2016

The Citizens Foundation (AAP Trust) | Karachi, Pakistan

Provided administrative and technical assistance to the team. Salient responsibilities and achievements included;

- Successfully managed the recruitment and placement of learning coaches for TCF's Alumni Development Program.
- Built partnerships with multiple educational institutions in Karachi for volunteer recruitment and placement.
- Contributed in the curriculum development for the TCF College induction program by identifying and incorporating the latest education standards.
- Led university admission campaigns and trainings at multiple TCF schools.

EDUCATION

Master's in Global Policy

Boston University | Boston, US | 2018 - 2019

Bachelor's in Business Administration

IBA Karachi | Karachi, Pakistan | 2011 - 2015

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Planning and Monitoring

Research

Data Analytics (R and Python)

Project Management

Donor Reporting

Financial Management

Impact Evaluation

Creativity

Resiliency and Persistence

Communication

Strategic Planning

Innovative Problem Solving

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

• Fulbright Scholar 2018 - 2019

Awarded to pursue a Master's degree in Global Policy from Boston University, US.

USEFP Fellow - Global UGRAD
 2014

Awarded to spend a semester as an exchange student at Delta State University, US.

USAID Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship
 2011 - 2015

Awarded to pursue a Bachelor's degree in Business Administration from IBA Karachi.

Graduate Student Researcher, Boston University 2019

Awarded to conduct a semester long research on the impact of free-trade policies on the rural sector in Pakistan.

CERTIFICATIONS

•	Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python - Coursera	Feb 2022
•	Python for Everybody Specialization - Coursera	Nov 2021
•	Introduction to Data Science in Python - Coursera	Feb 2021
•	Data Analyst with R - DataCamp	Apr 2020
•	Bloomberg Market Concepts - Bloomberg LP	Oct 2020

INTERESTS

Human Development | Sustainability | Climate Science | Data Analytics and Visualization (R, Python, and Tableau) | Electronic Music | Financial Technology | Impact Investments